不，哈沙德
No, Harshad.
不行
No.
这太危险了
It's very risky.
风险是生活的调味品
Risk is the spice of life.
什么？
What?
先生，我问你
Sir, tell me one thing.
印度有几个大公牛？
How many big bulls are there in India?
只有两个，你和我
Only two. You and I.
所以，我们是天生一对
So, we are made for each other.
我们有了现在的地位，是因为我们冒了风险
We've reached where we are, because we took risks.
对吧？
Right?
先生，这很简单
Sir, it's very simple.
你只要以 Grindlays 的名义签发支票就行了
You just have to issue cheques in the name of Grindlays.
这对你来说只是一个即期交易
It's just a ready-forward deal for you.
但是..
But...
我需要..
I would need...
作为回报，我们会从 Grindlays 那里拿到收据
...BRs from Grindlays in return.
你会得到的，绝对会
And you will get them. Definitely.
交给我吧
Leave that to me.
只需要15天
It's just a matter of 15 days.
在15天内，NHB 将会拿回资金
And in 15 days, NHB will get its money back.
先生，德里的提议仍然有效
And Sir, the Delhi offer stands.
这是哈沙德向你保证的，先生
It's Harshad's guarantee to you, sir.
你会在议会中占有一席之地
You will get positioned in the parliament.
好吧
Okay.
“好吧”
[Pherwani] 'Okay. I'll do it.'
但是..
But...
如果出了什么差错
...if anything goes wrong...
那么
...then...
我付出四十年心血
...my reputation of forty years...
打造的名声
...for which I worked so hard...
... 都将化为乌有
...will go down the drain.
- 你明白吗?-先生
- Do you understand that? - Sir.
当消息从上面传来的时候你
Why are you thinking of going down...
为什么要往坏的方面想？
...when the messages are coming from up?
什么？
Huh?
我们受到上帝的保护
We are protected by higher powers.
早上好，先生
Good morning, sir.
你好，马德文，请进
[Das] 'Yes, Madhavan. Please come in.'
“你看到那份文件了吗? ”
'So... Did you see the file?'
是的
Yes.
这需要时间来消化
It will take time to comprehend.
这是个金融骗局
It's a financial scam.
我们需要用不同的方式来调查
We will need to investigate it differently.
骗局
Scam.
先生，这是大盗的新称呼
Sir, it's a new word for a big theft.
我明白
I get that.
这是金融欺诈
It's a financial fraud.
交易是很复杂的
Transactions are very complicated.
先生，如果我们深究细节，我们会陷入一个数字的网络中
Sir, if we go into details, we will get caught in a web of numbers.
所以，我想说的是，让我们专注于我们所知道的
So, I'm saying, let's just focus on what we know.
这是盗窃
It's a theft.
调查小偷只有一个办法，先生
And there is only one way to investigate thieves, sir.
嗯
Hmm.
继续
Go ahead.
照你的方法做，不要有任何压力
Do it your way. There won't be any pressure.
但是，记住一件事
But, remember one thing.
这个骗局比博福斯大50倍
This scam is 50 times bigger than Bofors.
而且可能比博福斯更加黑暗
It can be murkier than Bofors.
另外，政府和媒体..
Plus, the Government and the media...
会让新闻持续发酵
...will keep the pressure up.
先生，这又不是什么新鲜事
Sir, what's new in that?
我们已经习惯了
We are used to that.
给我几天时间，先生，让我把队伍集合起来
Give me a few days, sir, to get my team together.
印度储备银行行长？
RBI Governor?
- 我们要调查他?-[笑]
- We have to investigate him? -[laughs]
如果由你决定，你甚至会调查我
If it were up to you, you would even investigate me.
行长是指引我们的人”
[Das] 'But the Governor is there to guide us.'
他会帮你找到合适的人
He will help you out, with the right people.
好极了
Okay. Superb.
我马上开始
I'll get started.
- 谢谢-祝你好运
- Thank you. - All the best.
[德巴希斯]“这次你联系上詹姆斯 · 邦德了吗? ”
[Debashis] 'Did you catch hold of a James Bond this time?'
又一个神秘人
Another mystery-man.
这个詹姆斯 · 邦德住在这里吗？
And does this James Bond live here?
不是詹姆斯 · 邦德，是苏伯拉曼尼亚姆
Not James Bond. Subramaniam.
苏切塔，你不觉得这是个陷阱吗？
Sucheta, don't you think this can be some sort of a trap?
谁会设计陷害我? 哈沙德？
Who will try to trap me? Harshad?
别担心，他不是电影里的反派角色
Don't worry. He isn't a villain from a movie.
无论如何，如果我现在发生了什么事..
Anyway, if anything happens to me now...
公众会立刻对他产生怀疑
...public's perception will immediately doubt him.
他是一个聪明的古吉拉特人，他不会这么愚蠢
He is a smart Gujarati. He won't be so stupid.
那么，这个神秘的邦德从哪里打来的电话？
So, where did this mystery Bond call from?
公共电话
Public booth.
好吧我们都同意哈沙德是个聪明的古吉拉特人
Okay. Let's agree that Harshad is a smart Gujarati.
但是因为他，很多愚蠢的人变得焦虑
But because of him, a lot of stupid people are getting anxious.
这是个500亿的骗局
Sucheta, it's a 5,000 crore scam.
- 涉及到很多人-我知道
- A lot of people are involved. - I know.
- 从上到下-Sucheta 女士
- From top to the bottom. - Sucheta madam.
- 哦 你好?-是的，跟我来
- Oh, Subramaniam? - Yes, follow me.
请过来
Please come.
小心点，夫人
Be careful, madam.
请进，请坐
Please come. Have a seat.
在议会反对派的巨大压力下..
Under immense pressure from the opposition in the parliament...
政府终于决定采取更果断的措施
...the government has finally decided to take more decisive steps...
调查金融诈骗案
...to investigate the financial scam...
” ... 震撼了孟买证券交易所”
"...that has rocked the Bombay Stock Exchange."
“印度央行还宣布... ... ”
"The RBI has also announced..."
” ... 成立委员会，由副... ”
"...that it has formed a committee headed by Deputy..."
调查局什么都不懂
CBI won't understand a thing.
他们只会找替罪羊
They will only look for a scapegoat.
而印度储备银行... ... 为了挽救自己的形象，会让他们玷污其他所有人的形象
And RBI... to save its image, RBI will let them tarnish everyone else's.
我就知道
I knew it.
我知道他们都会背叛我们
I knew they would all betray us.
这正是我所担心的
Just what I was afraid of.
哈尔沙德，我们得做点什么否则..
Harshad, we need to do something, or else...
- 你在听我说话吗?-我听到了
- Are you listening to me? - I heard you.
我..
I...
只相信我的妻子和苏伯拉曼尼亚姆
...trust only my wife and Subramaniam.
这就是为什么我要在这儿见你，在他家
That's why I'm meeting you here, at his house.
现在，就菲尔瓦尼而言..
Now, as far as Pherwani is concerned...
恐怕..
I'm afraid...
我自己也做不了什么
...I can't do much myself.
为什么你不能？
Why can't you do much?
你为什么要告诉我们这些？
Why are you telling us this?
你是印度储备银行的行长
You are the Governor of RBI.
如果你想的话，你可以直接和菲尔瓦尼谈
You can talk to Pherwani directly if you want.
菲尔瓦尼不是一个三流的经纪人，也不是像哈沙德那样的暴发户
Pherwani is not a small-time broker or an upstart like Harshad.
他名声在外
He has a reputation.
我不能直接和他对质
I can't confront him directly.
- 看
- Look. -[clears throat]
不管怎么说，我有自己的局限性
All said and done, I have my limitations.
我是公职人员
I'm a government servant.
如果 RBI 真的想..
If RBI really wants to...
... 采取行动对付像菲尔瓦尼这样的人，那么..
...take action against people like Pherwani, then...
应该有外部压力
...there should be external pressure.
你... 明白了吧？
You... get it, don't you?
你是说..
You mean...
我们要建立舆论压力？
...we have to build external pressure?
但是怎么做呢？
But how?
没有任何实质性的证据
Without any substantial proof or verification.
国家住房银行给了格林德莱50亿..
NHB gave 500 crores to Grindlays...
哈沙德就是这样拿到钱的
So that Harshad could have access to the cash.
所有他们需要在账簿中展示的东西..
All that they needed to show in their books...
是一个简单的即时交易
...was a simple ready-forward transaction.
因为没有来自格林德莱的证券
Because there were no securities from Grindlays.
这就是哈尔沙德如何向印度国家银行偿还资金的
And that is how Harshad managed to repay the cash to SBI.
那么，你就是新闻出版社500亿报道的消息来源吗？
So, you were the source of News Press' 5,000 crore story?
晚安
Good night.
- 哈沙德-你好，费尔瓦尼先生
- Harshad. - Yes, Pherwani ji.
你知道发生了什么，对吧
[Pherwani] 'You know what's happened. Right?'
你为什么这么担心? 你的名字不会出来的
Why are you so worried? 'Your name won't come out.'
SBI 的问题已经解决了
Look, the SBI problem has been solved.
我不欠 SBI 一分钱
I don't owe a single penny to SBI.
[哈沙德]“放松点，不会有事的”
[Harshad] 'Just relax. Nothing is going to happen.'
哈尔沙德，苏切塔打电话给我
Harshad, Sucheta had called me.
谁? 苏切塔 · 达拉尔？
Who? Sucheta Dalal?
[ Pherwani ]‘是的
[Pherwani] 'Yes.'
- 她说什么?-她问..
- What did she say? - She was asking...
国家住房银行是不是给了哈沙德50亿
...if NHB gave 500 crores to Harshad.
问我是不是与此事有关
If I bailed you out?
你说了什么？
And what did you say?
哈沙德，他们要我出席委员会
Harshad, they have asked me to appear before a committee that...
印度储备银行刚刚成立了 Janakiraman 委员会
...RBI has just formed. Janakiraman Committee.
那么，你打算怎么跟委员会说？
So, what are you going to tell the committee?
你好! 菲尔瓦尼先生！
Hello! Pherwani ji!
无论我们喜欢与否
♪Whether we like it or not...♪
我们是旅伴
♪...we are fellow travellers...♪
在生命的道路上
♪...on the path of life...♪
给我一杯咖啡
Give me a cup of coffee.
今天 Sensex 指数再次崩溃... ..
Today the Sensex crashed once again...
... 在关于菲尔瓦尼先生的报道出来之后..
...after the reports came out about Manohar Pherwani...
国家住房银行现任非执行董事长
...the current non-executive chairman of the National Housing Bank...
关于他参与骗局的事
...regarding his involvement in the scam.
各方都要求..
There have been demands from various quarters...
菲尔瓦尼先生辞职
...that Mr. Pherwani resigns from his position.
观众应该知道，国家住房银行..
Viewers should know that the National Housing Bank...
是印度储备银行的全资子公司
...is a wholly owned subsidiary of the RBI.
印度储备银行行长 Venkitarajan 先生说..
The RBI governor, Mr. Venkitarajan has said...
印度储备银行正在进行调查
...that RBI is looking into the charges...
很快就会采取适当的措施
...and would take appropriate steps soon.
你在说什么，费尔瓦尼先生？
What are you saying, Pherwani ji?
辞职不是解决办法
Resignation is not a solution.
你为什么要辞职？
Why do you need to resign?
你只需要说你和这笔交易没有任何关系
You just have to say that you have nothing to do with this transaction.
就是这样
That's it.
那就是我的问题了，对吧? 我会处理的
Then it's my problem, right? I'll handle it.
至于用我的名字开支票..
And as far as issuing the cheque in my name is concerned...
这不是我第一次这么做了
...this is not the first time I am doing this.
这是货币市场的标准做法
This is standard practice in the money-market.
它可能是非官方的，但每个人都这么做
It may be unofficial, but everyone does it.
一旦我买了这些证券，钱就会转到我的账户上
Once I buy the securities, the money will be transferred to my account.
毕竟，我是那个偿还债务的人
After all, I'm the one who has to repay it.
这难道不合逻辑吗？
Isn't it logical?
每个人都这样做是为了节省时间
Everyone does it to save time.
我会尽快归还 NHB 的50亿
And I'm returning NHB's 500 crores, as soon as possible.
你不用担心
You don't worry.
你的名誉会得到100% 的澄清
Your name will be cleared, 100 percent.
相信我
Just trust me.
哈尔沙德
Harshad.
信任仍然是非常昂贵的东西
Trust is still something that's very expensive.
我决定了
I have decided.
我别无选择..
I have no other option...
只能辞职
...but to resign.
早上好
[Madhavan] 'Good morning.'
- 马诺哈尔，j · 菲尔瓦尼先生-是的
- Manohar. J. Pherwani ji. -[Pherwani] 'Yes.'
K. 马达文 调查局联合主任
K. Madhavan. Joint Director, CBI.
我们有你家的搜查令
We have a warrant to search your entire house.
继续
Carry on.
早上好
Good morning.
你知道高尔夫球中最重要的一杆..
You know the most important shot in golf...
永远是下一杆
...is always the next one.
我的下一杆是哈尔沙德
And my next shot, will be on Harshad.
最重要的一个
The most important one.
我只希望他穿着得体
I just hope he is dressed appropriately.
拜托，他只是个业余爱好者
Come on. He is an amateur.
他不知道挥动板球棒和高尔夫球杆的区别
He doesn't know the difference between swinging a cricket bat and a golf club.
但他认为自己可以改变市场
But he thought he could swing the markets.
这个板球运动员不会带着球棒来高尔夫球场吧？
This cricketer won't come to the golf course with his bat, will he?
我还是不明白
I still don't get it.
他为什么要来高尔夫球场见你？
Why is he coming to the golf course to meet you?
他绝望了
He is desperate.
即将溺水的人紧紧抓住一根稻草
A drowning man clutching at a straw.
- 还有一个-好的
- There's another one. - Okay.
有必要的话
When it's needed...
- ... 你甚至给驴子加冕-[凯迪亚笑]
- ...you even crown the donkey. -[Kedia laughs]
[哈沙德]“没错”
[Harshad] 'That's right.'
完美的说法
The perfect saying.
还有一个
There's yet another one.
在喀布尔，你不仅能得到豌豆，还能得到驴子
In Kabul, you don't get only peas, you also get donkeys.
你拿到了吗？
Did you get it?
算了吧
Forget it.
早上好，八木
Good morning, Tyagu.
太好了! 你今天心情不错！
Great! You are in a good mood today!
很好
Good.
多么荣幸啊，哈沙德
What an absolute privilege, Harshad.
大公牛
The big bull.
证交所的阿米塔布·巴沙坎
Amitabh Bachchan of BSE.
我们肯定做了什么善事 AK..
We must have done something right, AK...
让我们今天有机会
...that today...
见到你
...we got an opportunity to meet you.
- 你会玩吗?-我? 不，谢谢..
- Will you play? - Who me? No thanks...
这个游戏我玩不来
This game is beyond me.
我只能用棍子玩棒击木片游戏
I can only play tipcat with a stick.
你们继续
You guys carry on.
什么？
Huh?
普拉纳夫 · 巴伊
Pranav Bhai.
加油，兄弟！
Go peel them, brother!
没问题，先生
It's clean, sir.
弗瓦尼先生，你为什么不和我们一起走呢？
Mr. Pherwani, why don't you come with us?
你是说现在？
You mean, right now?
是的，我是说现在
Yes. I mean right now.
我在这里不太舒服
I'm not very comfortable here.
如果我在自己的办公室，喝着茶
You see, if I get my space, my tea...
也许我能问出正确的问题
...I'll perhaps be able to ask the right questions.
然后，也许..
And then, maybe...
我会从你那里得到正确的答案
I'll get the right answers from you.
嗯？
Hmm?
我将以我的报价买下他所有的财产
I'll buy all his holdings at my price.
大打折扣
At a heavy discount.
- 这会杀了他的
- It will finish him off. -[Kedia clicks tongue]
拜托，再想想
Come on. Think again.
如果你不买他的股份..
If you don't buy his holdings...
他连五亿卢比都还不了
...he won't have 500 crores to pay back NHB.
他将被彻底终结
He will be completely finished. History.
所以，请... 请把诱惑放在一边
So, please... Please put the temptation aside.
不
No, AK.
在这样一个大骗局之后，没有人进监狱
After committing such a big fraud, no one goes to jail.
一个月后保释
Bail in a month...
然后，一切都被遗忘了
And then, it's all forgotten.
这不是诱惑
This is not temptation.
我的建议对生意有好处
What I'm suggesting is good for business.
但这不是生意上的事，八木
Oh, but this is not about business, Tyagu.
这是私人恩怨
This is personal.
你别进来，先生！
Not you, Sir!
带他走楼梯
Take him by the stairs.
这样你就能参观调查局的办公室了
That way, you will get a tour of the CBI office. Okay?
你去带他
You come in. Bring him with you.
不多，只有五层
It's not much. Only five floors.
我们来谈谈生意吧？
Shall we talk business?
告诉我你出多少钱买我的140亿股份？
Tell me what's your offer for my 1400 crores of holdings?
百分之三十五
Thirty-five percent.
这个该死的..
This f**...
他嗑药了吗？
Is he high?
百分之三十五的折扣？
Thirty-five percent haircut?
即使在最糟糕的时候..
Even in the worst of times...
... 一个好的商人打折也不会超过百分之二十五
...a good businessman doesn't take a haircut of more than 25 percent.
你可能不知道，但这是一个固定的市场惯例
You may not know it, but this is a set market practice.
你误会我了，哈沙德
You are misunderstanding me, Harshad.
我不会给你35% 的折扣
I'm not offering you 35 percent haircut.
我给你35% 的股份
I'm offering you 35 percent of your entire holdings.
14亿卢比的35%
Thirty-five percent of 1400 crores.
总共是... 多少... 49亿？
Comes to... what... 490 crores?
既然你是来和我打高尔夫的
And since you've come here to play golf with me...
我会给你一个大概的数字
...I'll make it a round figure.
再加一亿，总共50亿
Take ten crores more. 500 crores in all.
你今天就能拿到
You'll get it today.
我知道这就是你所需要的
I know that's all you need.
[ Tyagi ]“今天晚上所有的股票都可以交易”
[Tyagi] 'All the shares can be exchanged by the evening today.'
来吧，接受这个提议
Come on. Take the offer.
那么近，那么远
So close, yet so far.
没有食谱，水牛来做饭
Without a recipe, the buffalo sits down to cook.
什么？
What?
你看..
You see...
一个不懂商业的人不应该做这种事
...a person who doesn't understand business shouldn't do it.
他毁了所有人的生活
He ruins it for everyone.
所以，让水牛自己来处理它的角吧
So, let the buffalo handle its own horns.
谢谢你的慷慨提议
Thank you for your generous offer.
如果你想让我淹死，我会把你也拖下水
If you want me to drown, I'll take you down with me.
我一直在试图解释，但你不愿意理解
I've been trying to explain, but you're not willing to understand.
你只想听你想听的
You only want to hear what suits you.
- 再试一次-看
- Try again. - Look.
这是一个简单的即期交易
This was a simple ready-forward deal.
好吧
Okay.
我们从格林莱斯银行那里获得了证券
We took securities from Grindlays.
我们付给格林莱斯银行50亿卢比
And we paid Grindlays 500 crores.
现在..
Now...
我怎么知道当时哈沙德 · 梅塔的情况？
...how would I know Harshad Mehta's condition at the time?
如果格林莱斯银行把钱给了哈尔沙德
And if Grindlays gave that money to Harshad...
这怎么是我的错? 和我有什么关系？
...how is that my fault? Why do I affect it?
不... 你说得太对了
No... You are absolutely right.
我只是想知道..
I just want to know...
你收到的那50亿证券在哪里？
...where are those securities of 500 crores that you received?
好吧
Well...
不是证券，是 BRs
Not securities. BRs.
你刚才不是说..
Didn't you say just now...
你从格林莱斯银行购买了价值50亿的证券？
...that you bought securities worth 500 crores from Grindlays Bank?
你刚才不是说了吗？
You just said that, didn't you?
现在你说，这不是证券，而是 BRs
And now you are saying, it's not securities, but BRs.
你是不是把我当成傻瓜了，你个傻瓜？
Do you take me for an a*****e, you d**k h**d! Huh?
两个小时了，你一直在循环，试图迷惑我..
For two hours, you've been on a loop, trying to confuse me...
“ BR，远期交易 ”“ BR，远期交易 ”
...'BR, ready-forward...' 'BR, ready-forward...'
谁来给我解释一下 BR 是什么？
Who will explain to me? What is a BR?
BR 到底是什么? 你能告诉我吗？
What the hell is a BR? Will you tell me?
先生，BR 的意思是银行收据
Sir, BR means bank receipt.
他说的对吗？
Is he right?
是的
Yes.
你说”银行收据”有那么难吗？
So, was it so hard for you to say "bank receipt"?
BR……BR……BR
BR... BR...
我们会再见的，这次谈话结束了
I'll see you again. This congregation is over.
我会在同一个地方问你同样的问题
And I'm going to ask you the same questions at the same place.
下次喝茶前告诉我真相
And next time, tell me the truth before having tea.
别再用你们市场的语言
Not in the language of your market.
用一种我这样的穷人能听懂的语言，好吗？
In a language that a poor man like me can understand. Okay?
你现在可以走了
[Madhavan] 'You may go now.'
出去的时候乘电梯
Take the lift on your way out.
接下来有你忙活的
You did all the hard work coming up.
现在..
Now...
不管你是搭电梯还是爬楼梯
...whether you take the lift or the stairs...
唯一的路就是向下
...the only way, is down.
我还有一句谚语给你们
I also have a proverb for you.
大脑更强大，还是公牛更强大？
Is the brain mightier, or the bull?
当然，你会说是公牛，对吧？
Of course, you'd say the bull, right?
因为你已经忘了如何使用你的大脑
...because you've forgotten how to use your brain.
否则，你就不会炫耀球技并抛出箴言给他..
Or else, you wouldn't have shown off and thrown proverbs at him...
然后不做任何交易就离开了
...and walked away without a deal...
你最好快点找到买家
You'd better find a buyer fast.
这些调查局的家伙都疯了，他们无所不能
These CBI guys are crazy. They can do anything.
他们甚至可以扇你耳光
They can even slap you.
他是个骄傲的人
He is a proud man.
还需要一些时间
It will take some time.
但是，只需要再一次盘问
But sir, just one more session...
他会毫不犹豫地招供
...and he will confess without a second thought.
他的自尊心受到了伤害
He is a man whose pride has been wounded.
像他这样的人会睡不着觉
People like him can't sleep.
他不会花太多时间的
He won't take much time.
好的，先生
Right, sir.
在那之前先把注意力集中在哈尔沙德 · 梅塔先生身上
Till then, let's focus on Mr. Harshad Mehta, sir.
他得到的时间越多..
The more time he gets...
就会找到自救的方法
...he will find a way to save himself.
但是，马德文，记住，他是个聪明的家伙
But, Madhavan, remember. He is a smart chap.
小心对待他
Be careful with him.
“他有一些非常有权势的朋友在保护他”
[Das] 'He has some very powerful people protecting him.'
对
Right.
[达斯]“在逮捕他之前，一定不要留下任何漏洞”
[Das] 'Make sure you leave no loopholes before bringing him to book.'
好的，先生
Right, sir.
等我们把他带回来，先生，就永远不会有事了
When we bring him in, sir, it will be for good.
我不会占用你太多时间
I won't take much of your time.
我只有一个小问题
I just have one little question.
你是投资管理部门的负责人
You are in charge of treasury and investment management division.
- 是的...-对吧？
- Yes... - Right?
没错，但你不知道你的下属..
Right. And yet, you weren't aware that your subordinates...
和哈萨德合谋进行这样的掠夺？
...were in cahoots with Harshad in such a plunder?
- 你看...
- You see... - [Khemani clears throat]
我的工作是为我的老板争取最好的交易
My job is to get the best deal for my employer, SBI.
- 没错-就是这样
- Right. - That's it.
执行实际交易是西塔拉曼的工作
It's Sitaraman's job to execute the actual transactions.
- 那是他的工作-好吧..
- That was his job. - Okay...
我是说..
I mean...
我不能为他的失误负责，你知道
...I can't be responsible for his botch-ups, you know.
对
Right.
如果他告诉我..
If he tells me...
他已经收到了证券
...that he has received the delivery of securities...
那我该怎么办？
Then what can I do?
-没错-我信任他
- Correct. - I trusted him.
但他撒谎了
But he lied.
好吧
Okay.
你信任他？
You trusted him?
- 是的-好吧
- Yes. - Okay...
- 他撒谎了-当然
- And he lied. - Absolutely.
好吧
Okay...
现在我明白了
Now I understand.
你知道，我有很多下属..
You know, Mr. Khemani, I have many subordinates...
我不得不依靠他们的工作
...and I have to rely on their work.
- 是的-我真的信任他们
- Yes. - And I really trust them. Really trust them.
但是如果我的下属..
But if any of my subordinates...
会做出这样的事情
...would have done such a plunder...
我会狠狠地扇他一巴掌，让他尿裤子
I would've slapped him so hard that he would pee in his pants.
但也许你的工作不允许你使用暴力
But then maybe your job does not allow you to be violent.
是的，其实不是
Yeah. It doesn't actually.
我的工作..
My job...
让我变得暴力
...allows me to be violent.
有时候
Sometimes.
只有一件事我想知道
Just one thing I want to know.
我是说，我很好奇，仅此而已
I mean, I'm curious. That's all.
如果你真的想控制西塔拉曼..
See, if you really wanted to exercise control over Sitaraman...
你本可以做到的，对吧
[Madhavan] '...you could have done it. Right?'
“是还是不是? ”
'Yes or no?'
是不是？
Yes or no, Mr. Khemani?
只要回答是或不是
Just a yes or a no.
我在我的船舱里会更舒服
I'll be more comfortable in my cabin...
什么? 大声点，我听不见
What? Louder. I can't hear you.
我的下属都看着呢
My staff is watching.
大声点... 请大声点
Louder... Louder, please.
别人在看着我们
Staff is looking at us.
你在看什么? 做你的工作
What are you looking at? Do your work.
- 我是说... 我在那儿会更舒服-是啊，走吧
- I mean... I'll be comfortable there. - Yeah. Let's go.
- 来吧，我们走-拜托，抱歉
- Come on, let's go. - Please. Sorry, sir.
你相信我，对吧？
You trust me, right?
- 是的... 当然-来吧
- Yes... Absolutely. - Come.
你的柜子看起来更像巴比 · 拉希里的，而不是你的
Your locker looks more like Bappi Lahiri's than yours.
这么多珠宝
So much jewellery.
事实上，我女儿要结婚了
Actually, my daughter is getting married. That's why.
为什么把你女儿牵扯进来，可怜的父亲？
Why drag your daughter into this, my poor father?
即使是在婚礼上，你是怎么得到这么多珠宝的？
Even for the wedding, how did you get so much jewellery?
我女儿用她的钱买的
My daughter bought it with her money.
- 好吧，她的钱-是的
- Okay. Her money. - Yes.
- 你女儿叫什么名字?-安妮塔
- What's your daughter's name? - Anita.
安妮塔
Anitha.
安妮塔有个"T"
Anita with a "T".
- 安妮塔，好的-谢谢
- Anita. Okay. - "Ta".
她是做什么的？
What does she do?
好吧
Well...
这一定是一份好工作，毕竟有这么多珠宝
It must be a good job. So much jewellery, after all.
好吗？
Okay?
她可以挣钱买那么多的珠宝
She can earn and buy so much jewellery.
但她不能有自己的储物柜？
But she can't have her own locker?
“奇怪”
[Madhavan] 'Strange.'
“事情是这样的，卡玛特先生... ... ”
'The thing is, Mr. Kamat...'
我们必须封锁这个柜子
...we will have to seal the locker.
- 先生!-不幸的是
-[Kamat] 'Sir!' - Unfortunately.
先生，婚礼还有几天就要举行了，你不能封锁这个柜子
Sir, the wedding is in a few days. You can't seal the locker.
好吧
Right...
你看，你已经封住了你的嘴..
You see, you have sealed your mouth...
所以我们还需要密封一些东西，对吗？
...so we also need to seal something, right?
- 否则我们就跟不上节奏了-先生
- Or we will be left behind. - Sir.
还有一个建议
One more advice.
你应该担心的不是储物柜，而是锁起来的问题
Instead of the locker, you should worry about the lock-up.
- ‘先生’-听着，如果你被捕了..
-[Kamat] 'Sir.' - Look, if you get arrested...
谁会在婚礼上送走你的女儿？
...who will give away your daughter at the wedding?
我很忙
I am very busy.
先生，求你了先生，先生..
Sir, please sir. Sir...
- 恭喜你女儿-先生..
- Congratulations for the wedding. - Sir...
祝你今天过得愉快
Have a good day.
先生
Sir.
“在和所有这些人谈过之后... ... ”
[Madhavan] 'After talking to all these people...'
“ ... ... 我开始感到... ... ”
'...I've begun to feel...'
你才是 SBI 真正的老板
...that you are the real boss of SBI.
SBI 印度西塔拉曼银行
SBI. Sitaraman Bank of India.
不是吗？
Isn't it?
先生，我什么都没做
Sir, I didn't do anything.
你所有的上级都说是你干的
All your seniors are saying that you did it.
每个人都在用你的名字
Everyone is taking your name.
你是贵宾，对吧？
You are a VIP, aren't you?
你乘飞机去 Palani
You travel by air to Palani.
是不是？
Do you or not?
我不知道，先生..
I don't know, sir...
- 先生...-嘿! 你不会印地语吗？
- Senior... - Hey! Don't you know Hindi?
- 泰米尔-泰米尔...-我来自德里，明白了吗？
- Tamil-Tamil... - I'm from Delhi. Got it?
用印地语说
Speak in Hindi.
没有上级的授权我又能做什么呢，先生？
What can happen without the authority of the seniors, sir?
你说没有上级的批准什么都不会发生
You say nothing happens without the approval of the seniors.
高年级学生说他们什么都不知道
Seniors say they don't know anything...
都是小孩子闯的祸
...it's all the junior's doing.
我该怎么办？
What should I do?
锡塔拉曼小姐，我对银行业的技术细节没有兴趣
Sitaraman ji, I have no interest in banking technicalities.
我只想知道名字
I just want to know the name.
告诉我所有参与者的名字
So, tell me the names of all those who are involved.
否则，在今天这个时代..
Otherwise, in today's day and age...
你将接受火刑的考验
...you will have to take a trial by fire.
明白了吗？
Got it?
想想吧
Think about it.
高年级的学生将不会受到惩罚
Seniors will go scott-free.
而你会被爆菊的
You will be f**ked.
你知道吗？
Now, do you know?
很好
Good.
中央调查局，今天冻结..
The Central Bureau of Investigation, today froze...
股票经纪人哈尔沙德·梅塔的银行账户
...stock broker, Harshad Mehta's bank accounts.
“所有这些都是对他... ... ”
"All of this is a part of the investigation..."
” ... 调查的一部分 ”
"...being conducted against him..."
” ... 因欺诈挪用印度国家银行的”
"...for fraudulently misappropriating rupees 500 crores..."
” ... 50亿卢比”
"...from the State Bank of India."
一切都毁了
Everything is ruined.
中央调查局开始调查了
The curse of CBI has struck.
我们所有的银行账户都被冻结了
All our bank accounts are frozen.
你现在能应付吗？
Will you manage now?
告诉我
Tell me.
去吧，孩子们，上楼去
Come on, kids. Go upstairs. Go on.
- 告诉我-你想听什么？
- Tell me. - What do you want to hear?
“啊? ”
[Harshad] 'Huh?'
解决方案？
Solution?
你和我一样拥有这家公司，明白吗？
You own this company as much as I do. Got it?
不要总是问我怎么办，自己也动动脑子
Don't always ask questions. Come with a solution sometimes.
我动脑子的时候，你总是高高在上
When I came with a solution, you were flying high.
“阿什温，一切交给我吧”
"Ashwin, I'll manage everything."
如果费尔瓦尼对中央调查局开口
If Pherwani shoots off his mouth to the CBI, Harshad...
那又怎样? 坐下
So? So what? Sit down.
动动脑子
Use your brain sometimes.
如果费尔瓦尼说了什么，PMO也跑不了，明白吗？
If Pherwani says anything, the PMO will also be mentioned. Got it?
怎么了？
What is it?
- 我们只是在聊天-让他们听听
-[Ashwin] 'We are just talking.' -[Harshad] 'Let them hear.'
你在孩子们面前大喊大叫
You were yelling in front of the kids.
现在大家都知道了，请坐吧，嫂子
Everyone knows now. Have a seat, Bhabhi.
坐这儿
Sit here.
哈沙德，你明白你在说什么吗？
Harshad, do you understand what you are saying?
你认为中央调查局会对总理办公室下手吗？
Do you think the CBI will go after the Prime Minister Office?
还有... 对这个费尔瓦尼做点什么吧
And... do something about this Pherwani.
如果他开口..
If he opens his mouth...
我们走
Let's go.
这个该死的麦德文！
This bloody Madhavan!
他对我政治迫害
He's on a witch hunt.
跟他讲道理... 我是说..
Reasoning with him... I mean...
根本没用
It's impossible.
他们只是想要一个战利品
All they are looking for is trophy heads...
陈列在他的橱柜里
...to display in their cabinets.
我很抱歉
Look. I'm sorry.
- 但如果把钱还回去...-别说了，哈沙德
- But if returning the money will... -[Pherwani] 'Stop it, Harshad.'
你一遍一遍地说把钱还上
You are repeating the same s**t again and again and again.
我们都知道钱不会很快到位
We both know the money is not coming anytime soon.
所以，求你闭嘴吧
So, for f**k's sake. Shut up.
现在..
Now...
调查组
...when Janakiraman...
将提交
...will file...
初步报告
...his primary report...
那些中央调查局的混蛋..
Those bastards from CBI...
他们会再来找我的
They will come again, for me.
“我知道”
[Pherwani] 'I know.'
我..
I...
不能再接受审问了
...won't be able to handle another interrogation.
我的德里之梦毁了一切
My dream of Delhi has ruined everything.
告诉我，我该怎么办?
- Tell me Swami ji, what should I do? -[swami] 'Hari Om!'
阁下，告诉我，我该怎么办？
Yes, Hari Om, Swami ji. Tell me. What do I do?
障碍是生活不可或缺的一部分
Obstacles are part and parcel of life.
你只要坚持信念
You just keep the faith.
我怎样才能坚持信念？
How can I keep the faith?
你说过中央调查局什么都不会做的
You said the CBI won't do anything.
他们冻结了我所有的账户，锁定了所有的东西
They've froze all my accounts and locked everything.
时间是打开每一把锁的钥匙
Time has the key to every lock.
所有的门都会再次为你打开
[swami] 'All doors will be open for you again.'
“现在... ... ”
'In this current situation...'
让中央调查局做好自己的工作
...let CBI do its work.
去他妈的
F***...
阁下，我会死的
Swami ji, I'll be doomed.
如果迈德文再审问菲尔瓦尼
If Madhavan interrogates Pherwani again...
他会坦白一切
...he will confess to anything.
我们控制了菲尔瓦尼的思想
We have control over Pherwani's mind.
请放心
[swami] 'Be assured.'
该死的白痴！
F*****g idiot!
爸爸
Papa.
妈妈！
Mom!
-喂-恭喜
- Hello. - Congratulations.
为什么？
What for?
菲尔瓦尼死了
Pherwani is dead.
你看见费尔瓦尼了吗？
Have you seen Pherwani?
他是个健康的人
He was a fit guy.
他以前像个职业运动员一样
I mean, every day on Marine Drive, without fail...
每天在海滨大道上慢跑，风雨无阻
...he used to jog like a pro-athlete.
像他这样的人会得心脏病吗？
Can a person like him suffer a heart attack?
我想他成了他自己的刽子手
I think he became his own hangman.
[拉吉迪普]“这些天来，你们所有人和中央调查局... ... ”
[Rajdeep] 'For all these days, you all and the CBI...'
“ ...逼高了他的血压”
'...pushed up his blood pressure.'
[ Kiran ]“我甚至听说这是自杀”
[Kiran] 'I even heard that it was suicide.'
“你怎么看，苏切塔? ”
'What do you think, Sucheta?'
“ 费尔瓦尼，自杀还是自然死亡? ”
'Pherwani. Suicide or natural death?'
- 苏切塔?-什么事？
- 'Sucheta?' - Yes?
“ 费尔瓦尼，自杀还是自然死亡? ”
'Pherwani. Suicide or natural death?'
你还好吗
'Are you okay?'
阿？
'Yeah?'
好吧
All right.
这是我人生中第二次明白
For the second time in life, I've understood something.
忧虑是通往火葬场的必经之路
'Worrying is a sure path to your pyre'.
我带了披萨回来
I've brought pizza from Open House.
来，我们吃饭吧
Come. Let's eat.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
苏切塔？
Sucheta?
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我想是我杀了费尔瓦尼
-[Sucheta crying] - I think I killed Pherwani.
费尔瓦尼是我们的主要证人..
Pherwani was our prime witness...
现在他永远都不会开口了
...and now he is permanently quiet. Finished.
“嗯”
[Das] 'Hmm.'
你认为... ..
'Do you think...'
“ ...这是... ”
'...it was...'
你怎么看，先生？
What do you think, sir?
当地警方显然会说是心脏病发作
Local police will obviously say it's heart attack.
他们想假装这是自然死亡
They want to pretend it was a natural death.
但是你知道，我也知道
But you know it and I know it.
太巧合了
That's too much of a coincidence.
如果不是谋杀那么..
If it wasn't murder then...
他们肯定是把他引向了自杀
...they definitely led him to suicide.
先生，我们只是在浪费时间，先生，我们必须行动
Sir, we are just wasting time, sir. We have to move.
我看了委员会发表的第一份报告
I have read the first report that Janakiraman committee has published.
继续
Go ahead.
我们登记一个案件，反对腐败的印度国家银行官员..
Let's register a case against the corrupt SBI officials...
越快越好
...as soon as possible.
然后，让我们进入斗牛场
And then, let's enter the bullfight.
你就是我们的斗牛士
You will be our Matador.
没人听到门铃响吗？
Doesn't anyone hear the doorbell?
惊喜！
Surprise!
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔先生
Mr. Harshad Mehta.
我是迈德文
K. Madhavan.
终于
Finally...
和你见面了
...I get to see you.
不... 我不是粉丝
No... not a fan.
我是你的信徒
I'm your devotee, My Lord. A devotee.
我可以和你握手吗？
Can I shake hands with you? Please?
我手有点脏
A little...
很高兴见到你
Such a pleasure to meet you.
你想看看搜查令吗？
Would you like to see the search warrant?
算了吧，我都亲自过来了
Forget it. I came here to meet you personally.
还有，是你自己开的门
There's one thing. You opened the door yourself.
我很钦佩
I'm very impressed.
你的房子很大
You have a huge house.
有多少平方英尺？
How many square feet is it?
一万五千英尺
[Harshad] 'Fifteen thousand.'
一万五！
Fifteen thousand!
好吧，这需要很多时间
Okay. It will take a lot of time.
来帮我的人一起……
Do one thing. Help my men...
找东西
...to find things...
对不起，不可以！
Excuse me. No!
这是突击检查，梅塔先生
This is a raid, Mr. Mehta.
你不能打电话
You are not allowed to do that.
你明白的
You understand that.
不允许
Not allowed.
你去……
Do one thing.
安排一些早餐
Arrange for some breakfast.
我听说这里的早餐很好吃
I hear the dhokla here is really tasty.
真的吗？
Is it true?
让我们尝尝，你好，阿什温大哥
Let's try. Hello, Ashwin Bhai. Greetings.
你不认识我，但我认识你
[Madhavan] 'You don't know me but I know you.'
过来坐下来
Come. Sit down. Come on.
大家好，很抱歉打扰大家
Hello, everyone. Sorry for disturbing you all...
嗨，孩子
Hi, kid.
你们在这儿干什么? 上楼去
What are you doing here? Go upstairs.
“上楼去”
[Harshad] 'Go upstairs.'
回头见
See you later.
坐下，这需要时间
Sit down. It will take time.
坐下
Sit down.
来吧，阿什温大哥，请坐
Come on, Ashwin Bhai. Have a seat.
伙计们，请不要打碎任何东西
Guys, don't break anything. Please.
叫人把早餐端上来
Tell someone to bring dhokla.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
我是认真的，请告诉你的厨师
I'm serious. Please tell someone.
不然我就得去厨房了
Please tell someone, or I'll have to go to the kitchen.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那么，15000平方英尺，嗯？
So, 15,000 square feet, huh?
真壮观
Impressive.
搜查工作让我的人精疲力尽，哈沙德先生
[Madhavan] 'You make us work very hard, Harshad sir.'
已经11个小时了
It's been 11 hours.
每个人都累了
Everyone is tired.
该吃晚饭了
It's time for dinner.
梅塔先生
Let's do one thing, Mr. Mehta.
你跟我们到办公室来
You come with us to our office. Kitab Mahal.
我们在那边吃边聊
We will have dinner there. And a little chat.
怎么样？
What do you say?
先生
Sir.
我们可以在这里吃饭聊天..
We can have dinner and chat right here...
不行
No.
我们在办公室安排了自助餐
We have arranged a buffet at our office.
这样
Do one thing.
你也一起来吧
You come along too.
好不好? 家庭晚餐
Right? Family dinner.
我们走
-[Madhavan snaps finger] - Let's go.
- 好的，先生-好的，先生
-[Man1] 'Yes, sir.' -[Man2] 'Yes, sir.'
先生，我们走
Sir, let's go.
来吧，先生，这边
Come on, sir. This way.
把客人带来
Bring the guests.
欢迎
Welcome.
阿什温 · 梅塔先生
Mr. Ashwin Mehta.
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔先生
Mr. Harshad Mehta.
我要拘留你们
I'm taking you into custody.
我们走
Let's go.
快点，押着他们
Come on, drag them.
-喂？-你听说这个大消息了吗
- Hello. -[Sucheta] 'Have you heard the big news?'
- 什么?-中央调查局逮捕了哈尔沙德
- What? - CBI arrested Harshad.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
这是真的
It's true.
他们突袭了他的房子，逮捕了他
They conducted a raid at his house and they have arrested him.
他们只逮捕了哈沙德？
And they arrested only Harshad?
不，他们还逮捕了阿什温
No, they arrested Khemani and Ashwin too.
这是基于我们的报告
So, that's based on our report.
“还有调查局的报告，听着，你能来接我吗? ”
[Sucheta] 'And on Jankiraman report too. Listen, can you pick me up?'
好啊
Yeah...
他们现在在中央调查局的监管下
They are in CBI custody.
所以至少要关两个星期
So we should prepare for at least 2 weeks.
然后，如果幸运的话，他们可能会得到保释
Then maybe, if they are lucky they will get bail.
我们能去拜访他们吗？
Can we go and visit them?
我们可以带些家常菜
We can take some home-cooked food.
不，嫂子，我们需要得到许可
No, Bhabhi, we need to take permission for that.
我觉得我们都不应该去那里
I don't think any of us should go there.
如果他们在拘留期间殴打他们呢？
What if they hit them in custody?
不，不，不会的？
No, no. How can they touch them?
大家好，我是印度时报的苏切塔 · 达拉尔
Hello, I'm Sucheta Dalal from Times of India.
我们能进来吗？
Can we come in?
嗨，我是苏切塔 · 达拉尔，这是德巴西 · 巴苏
Hi, I'm Sucheta Dalal. This is Debashis Basu. And...
苏切塔 · 达拉尔
Sucheta Dalal.
你就是那个记者
You are the one...
中央调查局为什么要逮捕他？
What reason did CBI give for the arrest?
你难道不知道吗？
[Jyoti] 'Don't you know, madam. Huh?'
你应该更清楚
You should know.
因为你什么都知道
Because you know everything.
不是你写的文章引发了这一切吗？
Aren't you the one who wrote the articles that started all this?
梅塔太太，我对他没有个人仇恨
Look, Mrs. Mehta. I have no personal animosity towards him.
我只是个记者，我想报道真相
I'm just a journalist. And I wanted to report the truth.
事实上我们来到这里..
Facts. And we came here...
是想听听你的说法
...because we wanted to get your side of the story.
- 你明白的，不是吗?
- You understand, don't you? -[Jyoti clicks tongue]
我什么都不明白
I don't understand anything.
我不明白..
I don't understand...
中央调查局怎么能把阿什温和哈尔沙德从家里带走？
...how CBI can just take Ashwin Bhai and Harshad from home?
后来，我们才知道他们被捕了
Later, we come to know that they've been arrested.
我不明白..
I don't understand...
在我们国家，这么多的恐怖分子..
...that in our country, so many terrorists...
罪犯和腐败的领导人到处游荡
...criminals and corrupt leaders are roaming about freely...
但中央调查局不去逮捕他们，为什么？
...but CBI won't arrest them. Why?
因为哈沙德对这个国家是个威胁
Because Harshad is a threat to the country.
不是吗？
Isn't it?
你一定也是这么想的
You must be thinking this too.
我也不明白..
I also don't understand...
出了问题
...agreed, there's been a problem...
来调查一下
Investigate it.
谁在阻止你？
Who is stopping you?
[乔蒂]“我们就在这里”
[Jyoti] 'We will be right here.'
看看这房子
Look at this house.
看看住在这里的人们
Look at the people living here.
我们是国家的威胁吗？
Are we a threat to the country?
女士，一个男人的故事对你来说比他本人更重要
Madam, a man's story is more important to you, than the man himself.
这就是事实
That's the fact.
你好
Hello.
你跟我说这个干吗? 把电话放下
Why are you telling me? Put the phone down.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
哈沙德被捕了
Harshad's been arrested.
现在？
Now?
现在怎么办？
Now, what?
他告诉我股价会上涨
He told me that the market will rise.
我借钱去投资，现在被套牢了
I borrowed money on interest. Now I am stuck.
当人们知道哈沙德被捕的那一刻..
The moment people come to know that Harshad has been arrested...
他们会来这里缠着我们要债
...they will come here, pestering us to return their money.
我们到哪里去弄钱？
Where will we get the money?
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔是小偷
[Crowd] 'There is a cry everywhere, that Harshad Mehta is the thief.'
'There is a cry everywhere, that Harshad Mehta is the thief.'
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔是小偷
梅塔先生，你觉得我们的办公室怎么样
[Madhavan] 'Mr. Mehta, how do you like our office?'
没有15000平方英尺，你一定觉得很小
It's not 15,000 square feet. Must feel small to you.
很热，不是吗？
It's hot, isn't it?
要我打开风扇吗？
Should I switch on the fan?
我得叫个电工来
I'll have to call an electrician.
在那之前，深呼吸
Till then, take deep breaths.
从你的嘴里呼气，会让你冷静下来
Exhale from your mouth. It will cool you down.
很有效的
It works.
我们在学校上课的时候就是这样
We had the same problem in the school where I studied.
那里有风扇，但没有电
There were fans, but no electricity.
我就是这样通过深呼吸度过七年级的
This is how I passed the seventh grade. By taking deep breaths.
真的
Really.
算了吧
Forget it.
让我们从头开始
Let's start from the beginning.
什么意思？
Meaning?
意思是你什么时候开始
Meaning, when and how did you...
如何有计划地从印度国家银行偷钱？
...systematically steal from the State Bank of India?
说吧
Go on.
告诉我，我们有的是时间
Tell me. We have a lot of time.
说吧，告诉我细节
Go on. Tell me in detail.
你要保持沉默多久，梅塔先生？
How long will you stay mum, Mr. Mehta?
西塔拉曼把一切都告诉我了
Sitaraman has told me everything.
所以我建议你..
That's why I advise you...
说出真相
...to tell the truth.
否则..
Otherwise...
我在你家吃了什么?炸饼
What did I have at your house? Gathia.
我会把你的脸揍成炸饼
I'll turn your b***s into gathia.
明白了吗？
Got it?
所以，我请求你双手合十..
[Madhavan] 'So, I request you with folded hands...'
告诉我
'...to tell me.'
你是怎么处理从印度国家银行抢来的钱？
What did you do with the money you looted from State Bank of India?
我没有抢劫任何钱
I haven't looted any money.
我已经把所有的钱都还上了
I've paid back everything.
好吧
Okay.
你是从哪里得到这笔钱来偿还的？
And from where did you get the money to repay it?
一定是从什么地方来的？
It must have come from somewhere?
拆了东墙补西墙
One theft to hide another... then another, to hide that one...
你已经偷了这么多东西，要把它们全部找出来还需要时间
You've made so many thefts, it will take time to uncover all of them.
“在那之前... ”
'Till then...'
就住在这里吧
'...be our guest.'
哈沙德没有得到保释
Harshad didn't get bail.
为什么？
Why?
他们说想进一步调查他
They said that they want to investigate him further.
他们调查完你了吗？
Are they done investigating you?
哈沙德是现在唯一被拘留的人
Harshad is the only one in custody now.
阿什温大哥，还有一件事
Ashwin Bhai, there's one thing.
特别法庭指定了一个监护人..
The special court had appointed a custodian...
我知道
I know...
他们想扣押我们所有的资产
He wants to attach all our assets.
是的，这是我们所有资产的细节
Yes. This is the detail of all our assets.
你和哈萨德得在这上面签字
You and Harshad need to sign this.
给我
-[Ashwin sighs] - Give.
给我一支笔
Give me a pen.
如果法庭下令,
Now if the court has ordered it,
我们必须附加资产
we will have to attach the assets.
我们还有什么选择？
What option do we have?
阿什温大哥，至少看一眼吧？
Ashwin Bhai, at least glance at them once?
你已经看过了，是不是? 那就够了
You've seen it, haven't you? That's enough.
好吧
Fine.
你必须改变你的策略
You have to change your strategy.
粉碎他的希望
Crush his hopes.
让他相信如果他不合作..
Make him believe that if he doesn't co-operate...
他会在监狱里度过余生
...he will rot in custody for the rest of his life.
照我说的做
-[Madhavan inhales] - Just do that.
你知道起诉你的案件有多少吗？
Do you know the number of cases against you?
31个
Thirty-one.
欺诈 SBI
Defrauding SBI.
银行汇票贴现案
UCO Bank bill discounting case.
马鲁蒂 · 乌德约格诈骗案
Maruti Udyog defrauding case.
SBI Cap 诈骗案
SBI Cap defrauding case.
也就是说..
That means...
如果你在一个案件中获得保释，就会有第二个
If you get bail in one case, there will be a second.
如果第二个给你保释，还会有第三个，以此类推
If you get bail in the second case, there will be a third.
你已经完蛋了
You're going to be so badly b******d...
再也见不到外面的太阳
...that you won't be able to stitch your bum back ever.
怎么了? 蚊子太多了
[Madhavan] 'What happened? Too many mosquitoes?'
顺便说一下，还有更多的好消息
By the way, there's more good news.
执法部门想见你
Enforcement Directorate wants to meet you.
[迈达文]“关于一起违反外汇规定的案件”
[Madhavan] 'Regarding a case of foreign currency violation.'
也就是说，等我调查完了
That means, when I'm done...
他们就会开始纠缠你
...they will start badgering you.
这不是很好吗？
Isn't it good?
给他带些驱蚊剂
Bring him some mosquito repellent.
不可能，先生
Not possible, sir.
来吧，给他点..
C'mon, give him some...
我们不能，先生
We can't, sir.
蚊子会吸光他的血，锁上门
The mosquitoes will suck all his blood. Lock it.
这就是哈尔沙德故事的结局..
This is the end of the Harshad Mehta story...
如我们所知
...as we know it.
从贫穷到富有..
From rags to riches...
再从富有变成狗
...to the dogs.
为什么这么严肃，凯迪亚？
Why so serious, Kedia?
拜托，你们难道不知道..
Come on. Don't you guys know...
人们和媒体都在追查哈沙德
...people and the press are after Harshad...
但是 RBI 的调查还在继续
...but RBI's investigation is still on.
哈沙德的被捕意味着迟早..
And Harshad's arrest means, sooner or later...
他们会把目光转移到其他人身上
...they will move on to other people.
- 像我们这样的人-得了吧，凯迪亚
- People like us. - Come on, Kedia.
这里是印度
This is India.
没有人敢碰这里的外资银行
No one dares to touch foreign banks here.
但我不经营外资银行
But I don't run a foreign bank.
那又怎样？
So?
他们会把你关进监狱吗？
Are they going to put you in jail?
来吧，喝酒
-[laughs] -'Come on. Drink up.'
好了，不会有事的
Come on, Kedia. Nothing is going to happen.
我是从监狱打来的
I'm calling from the jail.
我别无选择
I didn't have any other option.
“哈沙德，你从监狱打电话给我，是在增加你的麻烦”
'Harshad, by calling me from the jail you are increasing your trouble.'
还能增加多少？
How much can it increase?
我快死了
I'm dying here.
这是我们所有人最后的机会
Look, this is the last chance for all of us.
如果我倒下了，我会把所有人都拖下水
If I go down, I'll take everyone down with me.
我会想办法的
'I'll do something.'
我得和几个人商量一下
'I'll have to discuss it with a few people.'
没时间了，阁下
There's no time for that, Swami ji.
这个消息，首相应该..
This message, the Prime Minister should...
把我的信息直接传达给首相
Convey my message directly to the PM.
你是在威胁这个国家的总理吗
'Are you threatening the prime minister of this country?'
你无所不知，阁下
You are omniscient, Swami ji.
你什么都知道
You know everything.
来吧，伙计，把我关起来
Come buddy, lock me up.